Ow!
Hold still.
Okay, all done.
Thanks.
Tohsaka?
I'm making dinner.
Dinner? Now?
Of course.
Can't come up with decent ideas on an empty stomach, right?
I did a lot of thinking afterward.
About why I started fighting in the Grail War.
About what I wanted to accomplish.
And?
At first it was just because I got dragged into it,
but that makes no difference.
I like champions of justice,
and I want to follow their example.
So I have to protect people.
Master or not, Saber or not...
I'm going to fight all the same.
Oh.
Look, this is serious. At least pay attention.
I am paying attention.
The idea of others dying bothers you more than the idea of your own death.
So you've decided to keep fighting despite your weakness, right?
Y-Yeah.
What's with you?
You look like a squirrel that bit into a candy instead of a nut.
I just assumed you'd be against it.
Of course I'm against it.
But after you saved me like that, I can hardly object, can I?
Plus, I've also learned that you'll do it even if I try to stop you.
Then we're still partners?
I guess.
Anyway, I'd lose sleep worrying if I left you to your own devices.
Besides...
To put it in your terms, I don't exactly hate you.
And your cooking is good.
So that's how I feel about it,
and you're okay still working with me, right?
I need a refill!
For now, our enemy is Caster.
The Princess of Colchis
She's protected by Kuzuki,
a close-combat fighter,
and Archer, who's gone over to her side.
And it's only a matter of time before Saber falls under her control.
Yeah, once Saber's resistance wears out,
we really won't have any chance.
Exactly. Do you have any ideas?
Hear me out, and don't get mad.
Could we work with other Masters?
It's all right.
Actually, I was thinking the same thing.
We still don't know who Lancer's Master is, so that's out,
but we might have a shot with Illyasviel.
How do we find her, though?
I have an idea of where she might be.
My father told me something long ago.
He said that the Einzberns have a villa in the forest outside of town.
Why can I not find it?
There is no Holy Grail here.
No. That can't possibly be true.
The Holy Grail War's overseer would never let the catalyst—his trump card—out of sight.
Welcome, Caster!
It is my great honor to be able to welcome
a great pioneer of magecraft, the Princess of Colchis.
Now, do you have any questions?
Should I have introduced myself?
No, I understand the situation.
I have been summoned by the Holy Grail
and brought back to life in this era with you as my Master.
Yes, that is what a Servant is.
And that is the Holy Grail War.
That's a mage Servant for you.
I'm glad I don't have to explain everything.
Oh, would you care for a drink?
After all, coming from more than 3,000 years is a long way.
I'm sure you must be tired.
Or would you like a bath first?
I appreciate your thoughtfulness, but before that...
you have not yet told me your name.
I'm Atrum Galliasta.
I'm a Master sent here by the Mages Association.
My reasons for winning the Grail
are the growth of the magical world and securing a quiet future.
Does that satisfy your curiosity?
What do you mean by "a quiet future"?
A world where there are none who threaten me.
It's not as bad as it was in your time,
but humans are still as stupid as ever.
The greater the self-defense measures, the better.
Something like that dragon Noble Phantasm of yours, for instance.
Something like...
Hang on, Caster.
What's that Noble Phantasm?
The summoning of a dragon from the age of myths...
I thought that's what the Noble Phantasm of Princess Medea was?
My apologies, Master.
My Noble Phantasm is a conceptual one, given shape by my nature.
Even though I possess the knowledge to summon a dragon,
I would not be able to control it.
Well, isn't that a shame!
She can't even use a dragon!
What a ridiculous Servant did I pick!
And your Noble Phantasm is Spell-breaking...
Oh, Princess Medea was the first case of fratricide, wasn't she?
For a woman who's done nothing but betray others...
...isn't that oath-breaking dagger very fitting?
But I won't cast you aside, Caster.
Every Servant has its uses.
As long as you remain a clever woman, I'll break you in properly.
My family is still new to the Mages' Association.
So one reason I'm fighting in this Grail War is to gain prestige.
El-Melloi didn't take the last war seriously, but I'm different.
I fully intend to win.
For one thing, I've invested a lot more capital.
Do you think a purchased title is purchased glory?
No. One should use every tool at one's disposal.
If you intend to use wealth as a weapon,
I'm sure there are strategies tailored to that.
Don't get the wrong idea.
As a mage, I've made preparations to overwhelm the other Masters.
Come.
I'll prove it to you.
Is this an alchemy workshop?
My family uses a magic system that generates mana via offerings.
Well, it's a primitive curse that relies on human sacrifice.
This workshop is a more modern and efficient version
of the original system.
I'll make one to show you.
It works best when the raw materials are fresh.
How's that? Ordinarily this would take a month to create, but I did it in the blink of an eye.
Oh, and don't worry about the raw materials.
I won't procure them in Fuyuki.
I bought these from other—
This is too inefficient.
Using all these lives to create such a tiny crystal
is the act of a third-rate mage.
What...
What did you do?
How could you create mana from an empty kiln?
Empty?
Oh. So this appears empty to the eyes of you modern mages?
Your mana-generating technique must be one level—
no, a whole world below mine.
B-But what about the incantation?
I devoted all I had to designing this workshop
for the purpose of omitting the incantation process.
The transmutation incantation alone
is supposed to take three days and nights!
I have no need for incantations.
For me, magic is simply something to command.
Forgive me for acting out of turn,
but I ask that you close this workshop.
Throwing away lives is unwise.
As a mage, I cannot abide a workshop that generates such a loss.
Ah, it would appear that I have failed to grasp the true nature of a Servant.
By my Command Spell, I order you:
do not use your Noble Phantasm on me.
I wouldn't want to be stabbed in the back by a treacherous witch.
Witch?
He called me a witch?
Everyone I meet calls me a witch.
You say that Caster is too much for you to handle?
It's not a matter of ability but of trust.
Her sense of values is just too different from ours.
She is a woman who can cast magic with a wave of her fingers.
To her, human life is as worthless as paper.
After all, this woman killed her rival in love
by burning her alive in her castle.
I'd have to be crazy to trust her.
I see.
That is how you have interpreted the stories of Princess Medea?
My job is to accommodate the Masters' wishes as best I can.
All the more so for those with the Mages' Association's backing.
At this stage, the Grail has selected five Masters.
Two positions remain vacant.
I was hoping you'd say that!
It's possible for me to make a pact with a different Servant, right?
Though unprecedented, it is possible.
But before that,
something must be done about the Servant
to whom you are currently bound.
No matter how gifted she might be in magic,
she's nothing but a vixen whose only trick is deceiving men.
I've already laid the groundwork.
Still, better safe than sorry, Father Kotomine.
I want you to give this to Lancer's Master.
She owes me at least this much as a
fellow Mages' Association participant.
What is it?
Oh, it's only a contract selling the right to dispose of Caster.
If she agrees, I'll be rid of Caster
without having to waste a Command Spell.
To Lancer's Master, you say?
Like Servant, like Master.
Neither of them has any luck at all.
What is the meaning of this?
I took it upon myself to dismantle your workshop.
I shall take you to a more suitable place for fortification.
Dismantle, eh?
What about my supplies?
I still had around fifty left.
They were unnecessary, so I freed them.
Then what is this "more suitable" location?
The heart of this ritual.
The place where the Greater Grail rests.
I have located a natural fortress that repels Servants.
If you do as I say, I shall take you there, Master.
That won't be necessary.
I no longer require your services, Medea.
I order you by my Command Spell:
kill yourself, Caster.
What's going on?
It takes more than one?
I once again order you by my Command Spell:
terminate yourself, Caster!
What a foolish Master you are.
Have you forgotten what my Noble Phantasm is?
Rule Breaker...
But I used a Command Spell to forbid you from using it!
Indeed, I cannot use it on you.
Thus, I used it on myself to sever my pact with you.
I-Impossible!
To you Servants, that's tantamount to suicide!
You won't be able to maintain your physical form!
Yes, but what of it?
You are about to die here, so is that any of your concern?
What is this?
What's going on?
I won't let it end like this!
The Grail War hasn't even started!
I haven't fought a single battle!
Not like this!
Yes...
It is a fitting end for you,
a man who desired results before he even began.
You treacherous... witch...
It's hot.
In the end, is this how I shall die once again?
Passed around for others' convenience, exploited,
reviled as a traitor...
All I wanted...
was to return to my homeland.
What are you doing there?
You believe such an outrageous story?
I don't think you'd have any reason to lie...
unless you stand to gain something by deceiving me.
Rather, it is you who has no reason
to help a woman covered in blood.
I could hardly ascertain your character
while you were unconscious.
Have you calmed down?
If so, we should begin.
Then you are saying...
You need what you called a "vessel," correct?
I thought your only chance was for me to become your Master.
Or was I wrong?
Go for wool and come home shorn, huh?
I see that even a peerless witch is surprisingly delicate.
I thought I told you to keep watch outside.
Oh, about that.
There are no enemies worth mentioning outside.
I could no longer stand the boredom.
That is no surprise.
The moment you changed sides,
Berserker became our only enemy.
Did you not side with me because you knew that?
Perhaps.
Haven't you even thought that I simply
wanted to sever my pact with that Master?
That I didn't care who my Master was, if not that girl?
I see.
We as Servants are usually dissatisfied with our Masters.
Are you saying that you are relieved
at being freed from babysitting that little girl?
A word of advice.
Don't assume that all Servants are like you.
A righteous Heroic Spirit...
...can serve only a righteous human.
You do not need to tell me that.
Twisted Masters summon
twisted Heroic Spirits because of their nature.
Then it makes sense that such a witch
summoned a fictitious Heroic Spirit.
I do not care what you think.
Your life is in my hands.
Bear that in mind when you speak.
Understood.
Then, like the faithful Servant I am,
I shall strive to meet the expectations of my Lord.
Just a little longer, and the Holy Grail will be in my grasp.
For now, I guess we have to pin our hopes on Illyasviel.
Berserker is definitely Caster's natural enemy.
Is Caster somehow connected to Berserker?
Archer told me.
He said Berserker's true identity is Heracles.
If Caster really is the peerless witch Medea,
they should have met on the Argo.
It's like my sore spot when it comes to Kirei.
Everyone has someone they just can't deal with.
Hey, Shirou. Would you mind walking ahead a bit?
Sure, I guess.
What was that?
I knew it.
It seems her control extends to the entire forest.
But that means we just tripped her security system!
I don't think it's a problem, do you?
We came here to talk, not attack.
So it's better to let her know we don't intend to fight.
I get it.
Be careful, though.
It shocks you a bit.
I'll be fine.
Now that brat's really done it!
I know I heard her laugh just now!
She walked right into my trap.
Rin's really amusing.
You can always expect an instant reaction from her.
But I wonder if they'll get here safely.
Maybe I should disable a few of the traps.
Mistress, surely you don't intend to welcome those people in.
Wh-Why not?
They said that they're here to talk.
Plus...
There are things I'd like to ask him.
Mistress!
You're such a worrywart, Sella.
Even if they're planning something,
they're no match for Berserker.
As that may be, I can't condone this.
Enough! I've already decided!
If the lady of the castle says to welcome them in, you do it!
That's all the more reason for you to drive them off!
As the Einzbern princess,
you must send a proper invitation
and then throw an evening party,
in keeping with proper decorum!
Sella, you're being stubborn.
Also, what you describe is not what she meant.
All right, fine.
You understand now, Mistress?
In that case, you two go and bring them here.
Mistress?
I'm telling you to go capture them!
How about it? Do we need this?
It's only natural that as maids,
if we see wrongdoing, we'll exact punishment.
Sella, that was...
I guess it's an unwelcomed guest.
Ow!
That jerk, dragging me along with him!
Where the hell am I?
Is this really where Berserker is?!
That is not Shirou.
No, he seems like a harmless fly.
Let's deal with him and be on our way.
You two...
Are you Einzbern servants?
You've come at just the right time.
Take me to Berserker's—
Hold your tongue.
We have no time to deal with an unexpected guest like you.
Either leap from the roof and run away, or fall to this weapon.
You have ten seconds to decide.
Nine. Eight. Seven. Six. Five.
W-W-Wait!
Four, three, two, one.
Are you kidding me?!
What have we here? Homunculi, eh?
Nicely made, too.
Even though you are humans only in shape, you function as children of nature.
They must have used a fine mold to make you.
Sella, this man is highly...
I know.
Don't worry about me. Just get away.
Don't be afraid, now.
I shall pardon your disrespect, given your display of awe.
If you value your lives, be gone from my sight.
I shall grant you ten seconds in appreciation for allowing my Master to escape.
That boy is a Master?
Then we cannot do as you ask.
Our purpose is to protect our mistress from all outside threats.
Though you strike me as royalty,
we cannot allow a man who reeks so strongly of blood to pass!
Is that so?
Then fall like flowers.
I expect that the Grail's vessel will come running
at the sound of your screams.
The Grail's vessel...
You are Illya's enemy!
Shirou is coming here, to the castle where Mother once stayed.
Leysritt!
The mages never learn, do they?
One should never give a tool a human heart.
Humans are incapable of reciprocating your purity.
As long as I draw breath...
I will not let you near my mistress.
Oh?
Then you may see your duty through to the last.
Leys...
Sella!
You are the doll that possesses the Grail vessel?
I see that crossing a human and a homunculus
has given rise to a peculiarity.
You killed them...
Kill him.
Kill him right now, Berserker!
You heard her.
Then come, great Heroic Spirit.
Toying with you will relieve my boredom.
Shall we reenact a battle of legend here?
That's enough, damn it!
No way! Those were all Noble Phantasms?
I can't wait, Illyasviel!
Your defeat is certain.
Berserker won't lose to anyone...
because he's the strongest in the world!
A Battle of Legend
Next Time